♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 14=
It's you, Prince Qi.
I thought
some rat from the gutter
had finally crawled into the light.
Still talking tough
when you're on death's doorstep?
I'm impressed.
To lure me here,
you framed me
and forged evidence.
Surely you went to
quite a lot of trouble.
I did it willingly.
They've all got people on my side
in the Court of Judicial Review.
They'll make sure
you're found guilty and executed.
By then,
there'll be no Qi Yuan in this world.
Only a lowly servant
in my residence.
And you'll be at my mercy.
Your Highness,
you're celebrating too soon.
Your Majesty,
did you hear that?
I have been wronged.
Please investigate, Your Majesty.
Bluffing.
Why would His Majesty
come to such a filthy place?
If I hadn't come,
how would I know my good son
was running a private brothel
and forcing decent women
into prostitution?
And even
turning the Court of Judicial Review
into his own private den
from cronyism and murder.
Father!
Hong Xiao, you're not dead?
If she were dead,
who would testify to your crimes?
Prince Qi is ruthless.
He would definitely come after you.
This soft armor will keep you safe.
I was being foolish,
Father.
It was Prince Cheng.
He incited me to do this.
That's enough.
At this point,
you still drag others down with you.
Issue the decree.
From today on, strip Prince Qi
of his princely title.
- Reduce him to a commandery prince.
- Father.
Remain confined at your residence
and reflect on your sins.
Without summons,
you are not to step out.
As for Prince Cheng,
dock his salary for three years.
- Your Majesty is wise.
Qi Yuan!
Hong Xiao!
You set me up.
Fortunately, the evidence
from Yueying Pleasure House
did not implicate you,
Grand Preceptor Zhou.
In court,
you are the only one
I can rely on.
Your Highness,
don't worry.
I have many students and proteges.
They can all be used for your cause.
Qi Yuan
is far too cunning.
She must not be left alive.
Qi Yuan...
I'll make you regret what you did today.
Your Highness,
do you have a plan in mind?
(Marquis Yongping Residence)
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
What's wrong with you?
What could possibly hurt me?
What about this?
I didn't get this for you.
Not me.
Didn't you have Lianqiao bring this
to me
and tell me to take Hong Xiao
to see His Majesty?
I didn't.
Your Highness,
we're just working together.
If you didn't do it,
why are you taking it from me?
You stayed by my side all night
that night.
Yes.
I kissed you.
So what?
It was just a kiss.
What does that prove?
You can kiss me back if you want.
So...
So was it real
that night?
♪Memories return to where it all began♪
Xiao Yunting,
our cooperation
is over.
Get out.
Out.
♪One attachment I can't let go of♪
♪I have loved for your sake♪
(Don't be so nice to me.)
(I might think you mean it.)
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪
(Peaceful Residence)
Well, well.
This is a first.
Your Lordship,
you actually made mooncakes.
For the mighty Marquis Yongping,
what is so hard about making mooncakes?
Grandfather,
you made these mooncakes
according to seniority.
They are big ones
and small ones.
Even great-grandkid-sized ones.
Yuan,
the look of the mooncake doesn't matter.
A mooncake is like a man.
What matters is the taste.
Come on.
Dig in
and try them.
Grandfather,
these mooncakes are a little hard.
Eat the dishes.
Eat the dishes first.
Why didn't I see
the servants bring in the fireworks?
Did they forget?
From now on, halve the fireworks.
Why?
Grandmother,
here is what I think.
I looked over the household accounts.
We're short of funds.
A festival like Mid-Autumn
costs a shocking amount.
So I thought we should
cut the spending in half,
and use the savings to buy each servant
a new set of clothes.
So they can have food and clothing too.
Thank you, Young Lady Qi.
My dear Yuan,
you're clever and capable.
From now on, you can run the household.
I'll rest easy.
What?
Wait.
You said Yuan is going to
manage the household?
Wait.
Mother is still here.
Why should she be the one running things?
The one who manages the household
should be the capable one.
Yuan
has pulled the Qi family
out of the mud time and again.
She is the one
who should hold this position.
No.
Grandmother...
Sit down.
All right.
Everyone, start eating.
Dig in.
(Marquis Yongping Residence)
Bear this in mind.
Do not say His Highness sent you.
Miss Qi.
What...
What a coincidence.
Coincidence?
This is my home.
What's that supposed to mean?
Have her handle the accounts?
Yes.
Young Lady Qi
has a terrible headache over it.
What are you laughing at?
Find a trusted accountant
and go to the Qi Residence
to see what help you can offer.
Got it.
Just do not say I told you.
Sure.
Nothing.
I was just taking a stroll.
Did Prince Jing send you?
No.
The mooncakes in Prince Jing's residence
are awful.
I...
I brought him here to eat.
Awful?
Brought him here to eat?
Yes.
Lianqiao,
take six jin of leftover mooncakes
to Liujin.
Sure thing.
Uh.
That's so many.
I'm leaving.
Right.
I'll leave the accountant with you.
Feel free to give him orders.
I wasn't sent by His Highness.
This is
mooncakes?
Yes.
Made by Young Lady Qi.
I specially asked Miss Qi
for them.
These were really made
by Qi Yuan herself?
Yes.
She used
flour from Siam,
red beans from Persia,
molds made by craftsmen from Tubo,
and even this water
was transported
from Loulan.
Loulan?
Isn't that a desert?
Wouldn't it be short of water?
Anyway, it's there.
Just say whether
you believe in love or not.
If you do, eat it.
How is it?
Nice.
You should try it.
These mooncakes really
are unlike any other.
(Lofty Ambition)
Father! Mother! Zhen!
♪How I wish to hold onto
this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live this life
only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪